What a start, what a start.
I mean you can't do it any better than that.
That's one way to start a match up with a clean ace between Luca Raleigh and Talis there.
There's the old story.
If you can split two of them, they either both go for it, or at night of them go for it.
They both leave it.
That's what he got there.
And they both had to go for that one.
It's another beautiful serve.
That'll get picked up by Yamamoto.
He'll do a lot of that.
And then Nishida pops up far side.
That's contained.
Fernando will set up the Piper tag.
And that's a bit of a surprise.
Oh, that pushed too long.
Two attacks.
No kills yet for Brazil.
down 0-2 here very early on, but not perhaps the greatest start that the Brazilians were looking for.
Yeah, Luca really pushing it.
Nishida with another ace.
And again, he's got both of them going for it.
I mean, his lasers are fine-tuned here.
He's dropping it between two players every time.
Here's another one.
Nishida is just so strong, this time attacking the seam of Leal and Thales.
His second ace of the match and just three serves.
Now, Philly Blaine is saying, you carry on like that.
Let's have another 22 like that.
Well, is he going to fight with another one?
No, he's not.
That's a job done by Eugene Nishida.
Devastating burst of serving to open up this match.
Side out, we'll see Lucas Suck come back there.
He won this competition back in 2010.
Still going.
It's easier to say what Lucas Sackkamp hasn't had a major medal in.
I mean, he's got the full set.
His resume is extremely long and very decorated.
And club and international level opens up with a long serve.
Japan with the early jump here.
Not Suka serving Luccarelli, who just about deals with that.
That's Wallace with no real play on there.
A little whiff there, I think, in the middle from Onadira, and they pay for that.
Yohendi Leal says that's enough of that.
That's an attack matchup that's advantage to Brazil.
Leal attacking against Sekita, the smaller setter, but that time Leal goes hard cross court for the winner.
So Wallace, another one of these veterans with serve.
It's a nice take.
Look out.
Eugene Nishida absolutely rips it down there.
I mean, that's Thales who gets everything back in the backcourt for Brazil, but that was just too hot even for him to handle.
Nishida off to a brilliant start here.
That's his third point of the match.
The net serve from Aladira, side out.
Leal.
Oh, nice.
Nice.
Hey, they need a kick start.
Maybe Joanne Leal can provide it.
Well, Brazil gets an ace back this time from Leal, challenging that seam.
Yamamoto, we should have taken that one.
So Leal looking to level it up here for Brazil.
And he does with another ace and a completely different serve that's swirled away from Ran Takahashi.
Well, this is outstanding serving from Yande Leal.
And this is one of the hardest balls to pass.
Straight at you, actually going away from Ran to his line.
Line to line serve from Leal for another ace.
It's been a while since we've had a hat trick of aces.
And we're going to have to wait again.
It's a much better take from Ran Takahashi who comes up with third touch as well.
And it's a perfect one right at the feet of the back row defender.
Great pass leads to great in-system offense and Ran Takahashi attacking against Fernando.
That's advantage Japan all match long.
Masahiro Sakita, the setter.
Oh, he's found a nice.
I mean, Sakita's not known for his devastating serving, but sometimes it's about placement.
It doesn't have the power that Nishida has, but the placement is equally as effective through the seam and deep into the court.
The ace is coming thick and fast in this match.
Fernando goes for the quick inside second.
That's Flavio flying high there.
Flavio, which is so athletic.
Works hard to get around, Fernando.
Running that drift pattern.
floats away from the center and opens up that wrist away angle for the point.
Zekita with the forward inside set, that doesn't work.
So we'll have another go here with Yamauchi and they contain that Brazil and now they look to transition with Luccarelli ripping it off the block and Brazil starting to go through the gears here now after that slow start.
Now the Brazilian squad has to get momentum behind them, right?
Nishita started this match out with some quality serving, but Luca Raleigh getting a chance to get activated in the front row.
Scores on that first attack.
Flavio stays on serve.
No, he doesn't.
Side out.
Sends that on a little bit too deep.
Both teams have been very, very aggressive with their serves, which you like to see.
But it means you will get some deep long serves.
You'll get some net serves.
Here is Iran, Takahashi.
21 in a few days time.
full of youthful energy.
Again, it's a really nice pick up on Luca Rally.
Full of energy at 30 years old as well.
Part of the Olympic gold medal winning score for Brazil.
That'll be a fun matchup.
Luca Rally hitting against Nishita and vice versa, obviously.
Luca Rally winning that first challenge.
Fernando plays his club volleyball in Italy for Monza with serve.
That's picked up off the floor and that'll go out to Nishida who tries a little bit of finesse and the block was there to contain it and goes for a big power swing instead this time.
And again, Talis can't deal with it.
That's two that Nishida has zipped past the Brazil libero.
Now Luca's got stuck at the net.
It's the only blocker.
Nishida sees the alley and flushes that ball off the libero.
Here a Yamauchi.
It's picked up by Thales.
And the lovely angle taken there on the crosscourt from Luca Relli.
Now, Luca Relli had ankle all day to attack as that Suka drifted past the antenna on this move.
Luca Relli knows exactly what to do with that set.
Oh, my goodness, what a pick up that was.
So that's going to be collected by Luccarelli backcourt and hello Well, you won't see that too often Lucas are come straight into the net This opportunity there is Lucas got a great deflection On his block however the connection between him and Fernando Not firing there
Nishida, and it's another sizzler it really is.
That's sent backwards.
Luccarelli setting from about five metres behind the back line.
but they do keep it in play.
Now Sekita has options and he'll send it to Otsuka.
That doesn't come up with a winner either.
This could be trouble.
Yohan Delayal almost taking the head of Rantakashi off there, but he's kept it in play.
And then they come up with the winner as well.
That's typical Japan defense.
Just send everything back.
Yeah, great defense in the backcourt from Japan after a strong serve again from the inline.
Both teams working really hard.
Here's another dig.
Just back over the net.
Keep the rally going.
Lukareli has to step in and set.
And it's a block that catches Wallace on the way out.
That's a big bonus for Japan.
Nishida.
No.
Brazil, very happy to see that one go long.
Yeah, they are.
Deep Saira leave, saying that she'd have missed that serve.
Lucas at 10-11.
Sekid has to scramble around and Otsuka has done really well because the three-man block had all data get set there and bad things could have happened but Tatsunori Otsuka rubbed it off the block an hour.
Japan escaping this one a great serve from Lucas to the corner and then a really well-formed three-man block, but Japan gets the side out Another really good serve Talies has to hoist that one up there and Luke Carelli Can't get a winner, but Yamamoto setting from behind his baseline and somehow that's been shoveled over goodness only knows how
Yoendilay, I can't find a winner, Sekita.
As they go back in the system and did that catch the line?
No, it did not.
Otsuka goes too long.
That's a missed opportunity, Japan.
Yeah, it certainly is.
Otsuka just misses the contact.
Trying for the corner, but it was just long.
Wallace.
He's put a little bit too much under that one as well.
That really caught a thermal on the way over the net, didn't it?
A bit of a tail in on that one.
Pushed it way out of bounds.
Uandy Leal, the Cuban born outside hitter, zings that one too deep and we're getting a rash of service errors now.
Part of the reason for that is both these sides know you can't play safe at this level.
You've got to do something.
The borrow was set early on with two aces.
And a response from Brazil.
Now the service pressure continues.
Sakita's serve is picked up by Leal, Fernando has to scramble around and that allowed the block to get set.
And you know what, that might have been Ran Takahashi getting the final touch on that one.
That's a real bonus for Japan if Ran is getting block points.
That is him as well.
This ball has got to get covered by either Flavio or Lael.
They're both standing there, watching it hit the floor.
Hey, hey, let's get together here.
Hey, let's get together here.
The first thing is to hit two of them.
To the miss, don't let go of the line.
She can't let you go out, okay?
To the left, on top of the line.
He's marking the hand for him.
It's a good marking.
Keep it there.
Okay?
Get out of there.
I'm going to close the Miolo of the block.
Leave the risk for them.
Well, here's what's happened in the last 10 points.
Japan have opened up a nice healthy lead again.
There's such an air of confidence about this Japan squad.
We saw it in the volleyball nations league early this year and they went to the quarter-final stage, which was their best result.
You know, they hosted their own Olympics, got to the quarterfinals there.
They're suddenly banging on the door of being a top, top contender now.
Ooh, did Flavio get anything on that?
No, he did not get a touch on the way through.
Well, so far the middle attackers for Brazil not finding the court.
Flavio trying for the hard angle, but missing wide.
Sekita's serve is not particularly well handled, but the down the line from Wallace is an absolutely drill that Yamamoto, who just has to send it spinning off at a crazy angle.
The set from Fernando and Wallace able to turn that one hard down the line.
So that'll set up Flavio, Brazil with points to make up here.
Sekita will pick that up nicely.
Nishida is also picked up by Wallace in the backcourt there and now Wallace can try and scuff that one over and how many touches are they going to have?
Bit unlucky for Japan that time it was a good block move they got some hands on that attack as well just not able to play it cleanly out of the net
Flavio serving Otsuka.
Nice from Miyamachi.
Good execution.
Well, that all started with the pass.
Japan hasn't been able to run their middles very much, but they got a perfect pass and system that time.
They score the point through the middle.
Brian Takahashi.
Well, graduated from college, went straight into the Italian League, playing for Padua.
Boom.
Joanne Leal sends that back with interest.
He's in Italy as well.
We'll be with Pierre Chinz the next season.
Just a perfectly timed, big attack.
You see both blockers jumping on Lucas.
Leal can take care of that one all day long.
So Brazil staying close here.
Fernando can get him a bit closer.
He's getting a nice pass, but an even better block from Lucas.
Lucas was just one of the best middle blockers in the world.
So experienced.
What a reaction.
Just gets his hands up and over the net and the monster block.
So Fernando looking to level this one up.
Good response, this from Brazil.
That's got to be good and is.
I tell you what, Suga's found the corner there beautifully.
Just clipping that baseline.
Yeah, Suga's had a good start to this match.
It's his third point here in this opening set.
Yeah, he's the guy that's in the starting line-up with Ishikawa on the bench, the captain.
We saw Ishikawa come off the bench against Kata, and I know you were talking to Coach Philippe Blaine earlier in the week, and he alluded to just the management of some niggling injuries for Ishikawa, so they're not gonna work him too hard this early in the tournament.
It is all about managing your players through a tournament like this.
So whether we see Ishikawa or not remains to be seen.
What he's not ready to be, obviously, is a workhorse at the moment.
And that means others can step up like Otsuka.
Yamachi with serve.
That's gone.
Now, Fernando and Lucas communicating to each other after that play.
Lucas asking for a little bit of a higher set, perhaps, but this time he's able to score the point.
Listen, if Lucas is asking for something, Lucas is going to get it.
drilled by Lukarelli, kept alive.
Nishida with a clever push, Talies with the pancake to keep it alive as well.
And then the cross call from you, and now is perfect.
The Brazil offensive, Jung and Orton is starting to go through the gears here.
But what a save to keep that ball alive by the back row player for Brazil.
Tied at 18-all and Japan decides to use a timeout.
It's OK.
It will be a fight at TGM.
We don't forget nothing about the coverage, about everything ready for this.
OK?
All right, good.
Don't close, huh?
At TGM, we don't close fight.
And you keep fighting.
High and low.
OK?
All right, go.
TGM!
Philippe Blaine keeping it simple.
It's another good response from Brazil.
That's twice Japan have had a lead in this match, right at the beginning of course.
And they had a healthy looking one at the midpoint of this set.
Only to see Brazil comes charging back at them.
Let's see what Luca Relli can do here.
picked up off the floor.
Nishida is blocked out of it.
That's a wonderful one-handed dig from Ran Takahashi.
And it's just got to be pushed over there from Otsuka, who covered a lot of ground.
But him coming for another dig from Takahashi.
And then he's just blocked out of it, though, is Otsuka.
Great defense from Brazil.
They're all round.
Great defense from Japan.
Great blocking from Brazil.
Could have gotten the first one.
But Wallace comes through with a huge block this time on Otsuka.
scoring the point and finishing off that rally.
Natsuka will sit down as Ishikawa will come in.
That's probably not a surprise.
We knew we were going to see him at some point in this match, Nick.
and they go straight after the new player, as you would, of course.
You'll have a chance at swinging at this, and he just runs into the block, but there's too much on it.
The block can't control it, so Ishikawa announces his arrival onto court in style.
First swing of the match, off the bench comes in and blasting it off of Lucas' hands, and out of balance.
He's looking for it every time, using the sheet.
He's not looking at containing serves.
He's looking to put the pressure on every time.
He has the green light, as we say, to get after it as hard as he can every single time.
Lucas, 2019, with a little net skimmer from him.
Sekita sends it to Ishikawa.
That one's going to fall perfectly, perfectly for Yohande Layal.
Sometimes you need a bit of luck, and I'll tell you, you're in Leal at that on a plate.
Well, Wallace isn't going to get credit for the block, but the deflection is just as good as it goes right to Leal, and he cleans it up.
Lucas, Brazil going through the gears and put themselves in a good position here.
That was Ishikawa running into the containing block, but that's better.
Fernando would love to have that one back.
It got past the block, and I don't think Fernando was expecting that.
Oh, Fernando kind of charges in.
Catches him up high.
But a missed defensive opportunity that time.
Japan still looking for the point on serve to get him back level.
Ishikawa.
serves Leal, who handles that one perfectly.
We looked at what an angle.
What an angle he took there.
I mean, Takahashi was there to cover it, but just couldn't get a play on that at all.
It was too good.
This angle, challenging the middle, blasting it past the left hand.
An extreme angle from Leal on the left side here.
Yeah, Ranzakashi's got that cover.
He read it all the way.
You just couldn't do anything with it.
Wallace, another powerful serve.
That'll go inside.
Wallace picks that up on the dig.
Fernanda goes back side.
Long crosscourt sat there to Luca Relli.
And Fernanda, oh, just a bit out of sync there.
Will it get away with it?
Yeah, Flavio.
No, it's still going.
Well, that's Japan's scrambling defense at its best.
But in the end, it's a really clean cross-court kill from Yohande Leal that ends that rally.
Yeah, a great swing on the right side.
Some chaos throughout that play, but Leal getting stuck on the right side because they switched their blockers.
Fernando went to the left, Leal to the right.
That's why he's attacking on the right side on the counter attack.
This might just be a catch of breath time out.
So, both sides, they make pressure outside the block.
That's my king.
So, you should be ready for taking this, huh?
Hey, we tried to come to a quick, a quick, a quick pipe and open side.
Ah, because big, it was working so much.
Now Brazil's offense is starting to heat up in the later stages of the set number one now.
And the blocking of Japan has got to get a little tighter.
Not a lot of three-man blocking.
And that wing blocker comes off to play defense.
But if they're not going to block, they've got to play some solid defense behind the two-man blocker.
Well, can Japan come back from this?
First to 25, remember, with a two-point margin.
So Wallace looking to take it to set point.
That's a nice pick-up.
And there we go, game banner block.
I'll tell you, Flavio with Leal alongside him just wiping out Nishida.
Now we're going to see a challenge here come in from Japan.
That block had so much pace behind it off of Flavio, but it catches the sideline for sure.
It looks like on that replay.
But when it's set point, you might as well chuck a challenge down.
I agree with you.
That looked like it caught plenty.
Yeah.
That's one of those, what the heck challenge is, isn't it?
Well, I mean Japan has to challenge that one.
It's a good challenge at this stage of the set.
Set point then.
Wallace looking to serve it out, that slow start from Brazil.
A distant memory here, side out, but Japan will need three points on their own serve.
They'll switch it up and bring in Kento Miyada.
There's a precious situation for Miara.
Off the bench.
Come on, save three set points.
It's a decent effort with the first one.
Somehow, Lucarelli's got under it along with Thales, and he's well off net there, Yoandilay.
And still finds a clean winner.
I mean, Brazil just powering their way through that set the longer it went on.
And from a slow start, Brazil started to crank it up, and once they did,
Covered that second lead that Japan had they, but they won that set pulling away.
Yeah, they found themselves down by three points twice in this opener.
But once they regained the lead, it didn't give it up and lay out with a huge swing here to finish off set number one high off the hands.
That's as sweet as you like.
And Renan Dalzotto says, that's how we do it.
That's how we roll.
So a slow star, but a very strong finish.
Brazil securing the first set.
25 to 21.
And this is how they did it by the numbers.
Three to two blocks, five aces with three going to Japan.
The attack points very heavily favoring Brazil.
Great block in defense and great serving in that opener.
Setting the table for what was expected to be a very exciting match, Nick.
And can't really complain about that first set from both sides.
Good quality volleyball all the way around.
So placement for Brazil.
Looking like this.
A little more heavy to that left side of the court going after that front row outside hitter that's got to pass.
And for Japan, looking like this.
Once the big hitter's got into that stride, Wallace and Leal, in particular, Lukarelli.
Throw in a couple of blocks, and the Brazil juggernaut.
After a couple, a little bit of a shaky start for Brazil, they found themselves, Leal scoring nine points in that opening set.
Nishita with two aces right at the start of the set, didn't contribute, wasn't able to contribute very much after that.
Now only two attack points for Nishita through set one, two service ace points.
Defensively they did a number on him,
Whenever Nishida did try to attack, there's always a two-man block.
He didn't get any one-on-ones.
That was an exciting opener.
Let's hope set number two is equally as exciting here.
It'll be Fernando to get this second set underway.
Yamamoto picks that up, then Mishita can't get the better of Thales.
Backside it goes.
Neat, neat as you like for Wallace DeSousa, dropping into the feet of the back row defender there.
Wallace is just so deceptive on his attacking from the right side.
Faces angle, but has that whip of an arm that can turn it right back down the line.
Fernando does bring a bit of spite to his serves.
She takes everything off that one, so Keita can go back side and the Sheeter again is blocked out of it.
So it's scramble time for Japan and they almost scrambled something rather good out of that from Ishikawa.
Oh dear.
That's a big miss.
That's a really big miss.
Taishi Onodira won't want to see a replay of this.
Now, Brazil not happy with that no call on that third ball over.
That was clearly a double contact.
Great effort.
This is the contact that they're not happy with, but an attack through the middle from Japan results in that hitting air.
Fernando drills it.
It's another strong serve.
He's mixing up his serves really well.
Ishikawa picked it up, but his third touch wasn't particularly devastating.
And the block, I tell you, Taishi Onodera gets some redemption there for the earlier miss.
The stuffed block, straight back.
Lugarelli couldn't get it past the block this time.
A nice move by Japan, and the left hand there, shutting it down for the monster block.
Well over the net.
Perfectly executed block move there from the middle.
Nishida.
Oh, that's not a great take at all.
Somehow that's been rescued.
Tough to get a winner from there, but they are still trying to put something aggressive on it, and then Nishida does finish the job.
It all went wrong on service reception there.
Anytime it goes careering off in the direction of your coach and the bench, it's not good.
So Ishida restoring parity.
2-2, set two.
Oh, I tell you, that's another huge swing.
Somehow, they all got enough underneath it.
Wallace just has to shut.
Oh, that's a bonus.
What a bonus that is.
I tell you, Sakita and Ishikawa are not happy about something here.
Now the horn went off right after the serve was hit.
Bit of a mystery buzzer going off.
Yeah, it doesn't help anybody, does it?
I mean, it's the old cliche, this hands-off you play to the whistle.
Well, that was the equivalent of the whistle.
Now coach Felipe Lane has a legitimate argument.
He wants a replay, but he's not going to get it.
Nope.
The point stands.
It is 3-2 Brazil.
Luccarelli with a hot one around Takahashi, picks it up nicely, Nishida rips through.
Somehow that has gone into the net and Leal's recovered.
Oh my goodness, Luccarelli with the swing of the match so far.
That looked like a dead ball completely.
Somehow they've reacted and what a way to finish the rally from Luccarelli.
That's off the charts, good.
What a play.
Lukareli again.
Slappy angle served there.
Yamamoto has done well to pick up, and the blocks worked out.
Once again, Lukas celebrates sending that one back.
Lukas and Wall is pairing up nicely that time.
And Japan just can't find the rhythm with their left side attacker.
Forced them to call a timeout here early and set to.
Something was good.
Remember, when the opponent is playing good, go slowly.
Keep the ball a little bit higher.
Keep it stronger, high, long, and you can cover, and you can keep the ball working.
He knows these players very well.
He was the assistant to Yuiichi Nakagaiichi for four years.
He's been there for a number of years.
When Nakagaiichi decided to call it a career and retire,
And Philippe Blaine was the obvious upgrade in terms of just moving him up from the staff to the head job for the Japan Federation.
Sekita has to travel there, and Ishikawa doesn't really get a great touch on him, but it was enough sneaky stuff there to get the better of the block.
Yeah, Brazil working hard to get three blockers up after that great serve from Lukarelli, but...
Japan a bit lucky on that one to go off the block and down.
Yeah, hopefully Blaine's face told the story.
Sometimes it's better to be lucky than good.
Ishikawa.
Whoa, close, close.
Look long.
But not very long.
Not very long and nearly a touch of a layout.
Lucas at 6-3 Brazil.
Ishikawa with a lovely pass.
Really well kept up there by Lucas off the block and away, but they'll scramble this back somehow, hoisted up there by Sekita, free ball Brazil.
Where are they going to go with it?
A far side.
Thank you very much.
See you later, says Wallace de Souza.
Yeah, Wallace going with that fast set inside.
Look at that contact point, well over the block and down.
Bruno says golf clap.
He approves.
If he approves, it must have been good.
Lucas drilling it at Ram Takahashi.
His pass is terrific.
And he gets the benefit of third touch as well.
Lovely pass there from Ram Takahashi.
Ran just gets the one-on-one against Wallace Japan still got some damage to repair here on Adera Up next
Another big power for Swing through there from Yo-Ni-Le-Ao.
Sekita's had to cover an awful lot of ground there.
And that's a really nice take.
Ran Takahashi off the block and away.
But Sekita's getting all the credit for that.
The ground he covered there to make that set.
And the bump set too.
That Ron can attack high off the hands and score.
They needed that point in Japan.
back within touching distance here.
Onadera will stay on serve.
Fernando sends it near side and Yondele Al just rips that crosscourt.
Just nothing that Ishikawa could do about that.
Leal against Seketa and Leal will win that challenge every single time.
So much speed behind that attack.
Wallace finds nothing but Nylon.
So that'll be Sekita back to the service line.
Did find an ace earlier, but that one's not going to be an ace.
That's going to be Iced.
Wallace.
Wallace comes right back with a huge swing out of the back row.
So much line for him to attack.
Takes advantage of it.
Well, that's an illustration of what we talked about, Matt.
At this level, if you serve, it doesn't put any pressure on the opponent.
That's what's going to happen.
There's a serve that put pressure on the opponent.
The overpass ruthlessly punished by Luccarelli.
And Brazil just panning their lead here.
And Yamamoto sending it back.
Look really so.
We don't want it.
Get rid of that.
So Lael will serve into the net.
Tales picks that one up.
Fernando covers some ground.
Lucarelli with the clever push.
Yamamoto does manage to get there.
Rishi Kaur at the three meter line is wiped out.
Absolutely blown away there by Flavio, who had a long time to get himself set there.
You take it from that deep off the net.
You're asking for trouble.
Yeah, Flavio doing a great job to get his hands over and in front of the hitter.
Strong left hand there from a very veteran blocker in Flavio.
who will now go to the service line and flirted with the foot fault there.
But the overpass as Japan's receiving is just not at the highest level at the moment in this second set.
That's two or three overpass.
I think we've seen now from them in this set.
And that is usually what is going to happen if you overpass.
So Flavio will stay on.
Yamamoto picks that one up.
Lovely defensive work from Flavio.
And then a big swing, but nothing doing for Wallace.
It's come back somehow.
So Luca Relli goes for a little bit of touch and finishes the job.
So Keita was stranded mid-court, trying to get there and couldn't.
Look at all these hitters coming from Brazil.
Three hitters lay out.
Lucas, Luca Relli.
Manly the outside hitter.
Places it gently to the floor for the point.
Just floated down a little bit long, Flavio.
But overall, Matt, you know, we're only a second and a half in, but, you know, we were talking about that little bit of that invincibility thing, maybe not there for Brazil.
They breezed their way through a very good Japan team through a set and a half here.
They're looking very strong right now.
Really strong.
Yamauchi serves Leal.
He doesn't handle it particularly well.
But they get something out of it thanks to Wallace.
You think if you've got Luca Relli setting off court, you've got a chance if you're the defending team.
But Wallace didn't give them that chance.
So Fernando.
We'll now serve at 14-8.
Sends a short one in.
Nadira picks that up.
And that's more like it from Eugene Nishida.
The big left-handed swing near side this time off Lucarelli and Lucas.
Now Nishida, that's his first attack point of this set.
Japan needs him to score for their side.
Well, after that explosive start when he went off like a bottle of champagne, they just had the court taken out of it.
I mean, you know, they've given him nothing, Brazil, until that moment there.
Yeah.
It's run on a big one.
Too big.
Ran Takahashi picks that up.
Sekita has to travel.
Ishikawa runs into the block.
The block's there again as Ishikawa is off net this time.
And Lukarelli comes up to set.
Wallace tries to go cross-court.
Sekita will now send a cross-court for Ishikawa.
There's the block, but out it goes.
They got three in the block.
But Ishikawa, the captain, still managed to conjure up a winner.
Yeah, great set, that time from Sekita all the way out.
And three blockers, Leal, the last one to get there results in that attack going off his hands and then out of bounds.
And Ishida and Sekita check out here.
Japan look to try and mix things up.
Sending out Masaki Oya, the back-up center.
And Kento Miyara, the young opposite.
Ishikawa.
That's a clever serve.
But once Lukarelli got underneath, or Leal got underneath it, should I say.
It was one, two, three, finished by Lukas.
Just an absolutely beautiful angle that time from Lucas on that 31 set.
on Adira.
Really soft serve that one.
Wallace is blocked out.
Yamauchi got over there.
No, no, no.
You're not having that one.
Now Japan can celebrate that one.
One of their few blocks they've gotten in this match so far.
Right hand of Ron getting that block point.
Onodera.
Sneaky little serve.
Fernando brings it near side.
Leal down the line.
Doesn't get a winner.
Oya was there to pick that up.
There's a cross call picked up by Thales.
Fernando sends it inside another brilliant dig by Oya.
And that's going to come over.
And Fernando will set up Leal again.
And he still can't get a winner.
Oya with another one.
I tell you something.
Masaki Oya with three digs on that point.
And that's outstanding defensive work.
There it is.
Great pick up, but Ishikawa then hammering this ball on two.
Lavio made a good read.
What an effort from Japan.
Yeah, Ishikawa gets the credit for the kill point, obviously, but Oya dig off to dig off to dig, and now Brazil is saying, oh, we want to stop this little charge.
Renan's out, Dalzotto.
Sensing the momentum swing there.
The old story isn't that, when you come off the bench you always want to make a mark.
Let people know you're around and Masaki Oya certainly made an impact there on that point.
Now will that provide a spark here for Japan?
Onodera.
Serves Leial and yeah, what an angle.
Absolutely impossible to stop that.
Oh, no, Derro was there, but Flavio just so athletic, attacking this ball at such a high point.
Another angle for that swing.
Wallace.
17-13 in Brazil.
Still comfortable here.
Nice pickup by Ran Takahashi who will take that one off the block, but it'll fall nicely into the backcourt and there's another high one from Flavio.
That's some rescue for Moira, but I think he's gone the wrong side of the antenna.
Another terrific effort from him.
Well, it is a feature of Japan volleyball that always has been that everything comes back.
But even he couldn't sneak that inside the antenna.
So Wallace will now serve at 18-13.
Nice pickup.
The block was even better from Flavio.
So Ishikawa has to turn setter.
And Ran Takahashi says, thank you very much.
Flavio with a good adjustment, but just a little bit late.
Reaches to the hitter, and, gosh, he takes advantage of it.
Well, they're setting up for the block here, but in order to have a chance at the block, you've got to get yourself in play, and Miara goes too long, so it's Sekita who will return at Setter.
After getting a recharge on the bench.
Leal.
Where's that going?
Too much on it.
The overpass from Ishikawa, smashed back.
Well, hello.
That violation called against Brazil.
Flavio admits to it.
That's a let-off for Japan.
Ran at Takahashi.
With an awful lot of work to do here to get themselves back into it.
Fernando brings it near side.
Lukarelli can't get the better of Yamamoto and nor can Ishikawa get the better of Flavio.
is sent back with interest.
Lavio again patrolling the net so high against his hand so far over the net.
That's exactly what Brazil wants to see.
Well, they send young Darlan in there.
Youngster, just 20 years old, plays his club volleyball in Sao Paulo.
Sends in a beauty.
So Ishikawa's lost that.
Does that go in the record books as an ace, even though Yamamoto got a second touch?
Because if it does, it does well, but it should.
It should.
Oh, that's impact off the bench.
Darlan sends in a screamer.
You make one step, do you say?
You have to manage your high ball with this block.
What do you need to work on?
This is how the last ten points have played out.
Just padded their lead here, Brazil.
And they've comfortably got this match exactly where they want it.
And they haven't seen the last of Darlan serving either.
A big, hitting 20-year-old sent in another zinger, Yamamoto with an absolutely superb pass, Ishikawa.
Good enough.
Lucas was there.
That took plenty off that, so it didn't come screaming back there.
That's clever from Ishikawa.
That's a little touch.
Lucas just sending it out of bounds.
Side out, but Japan needing an awful lot here.
Yamachi.
Side out.
He knows where...
heading into set three with Japan two sets down.
That says an incredible meltdown here from Brazil.
Fernanda skims the net.
That's picked up by Rand Takahashi, who will now drive through straight into the block and back.
A trademark Takahashi pipe attack meets a wall of yellow.
And there's only one winner.
Lucas says, are you really bringing it here?
Really?
You taking me on?
Get out of here.
Sakita, that's the stretch.
Ishikawa stretch, does he drop it on the line?
No, he does not.
Set point, Brazil.
Just the wrong side of the line.
Fernando looking to wrap it up right here.
Can't do it.
That's Japan facing an overwhelming odds.
17-24 down.
They do have Nashida back there to serve.
He's always got an ace in him, but he needs seven devastating serves in a row.
Well, picks that one up.
Wallace wraps it up.
No, he doesn't.
That takes the net cord, not a touch.
thought at first that had taken a touch, but no, that skimmed off the net cord.
So they fight one off here, Japan.
Nishida though overheats that one, and that'll do it.
Brazil, dominant performance in that second set.
Not letting Japan get a sniff, grabbed the initiative early and never let their opponents get anywhere near them.
And it's a long trudge back to the sidelines for Japan.
They were facing a real headache here.
Brazil who trailed by two in their first match against Cuba came back to win in three.
But it's a different outlook here.
It's the Brazilians leading by two.
And it's Japan that are going to be thinking about the long comeback here because that was as comfortable as you like.
They had that slow start in set one, went through the gears here, they started fast Brazil and never let Japan get a sniff.
The numbers looking like this, 12-9 attack points, the four blocks to two, the ace serve, everything really stacking up in Brazil's favour.
And all those numbers point to the same outcome.
It's a comfortable
set for Brazil.
And Renan Dalzotto, who I think we will hear from momentarily, must be pretty happy with what he's seen.
Although coaches rarely are, of course, they're always seeking perfection.
With Brazil's head coach, Dalzotto, thank you for joining us.
Your team is up, two sets to zero.
Early pressure from Japan, but you've answered.
What's your message to the team going forward?
It's a very balanced match, because Japan is always strong in Batuta, like the first seven.
We made the difference in Batuta.
We had the tranquility to support Rebeni, the attitude, knowing how to play with a high ball, but the smell is very good in defense, so this third set is very important to have the right mind to start Rebeni.
Thank you very much.
Good luck the rest of the way.
Very strong from Brazil.
They are not taking any chances at all.
It did look like the possibility that they might be
stretched here by Japan.
It hasn't worked out that way at all and it'll be very interesting to hear what Philippe Blaine, the Japan head coach, makes of that first two sets and what he might be able to do to turn it around.
With Japan head coach Philippe Blaine, Philippe, down 0-2.
What are you telling your team now to start set number three in this match?
I want to be speaking with my team right now, so I will go to speak with them.
So, yeah, Brazil is being good, serving good.
The defense much better at the beginning of the match than usual.
So, now we have to find a side out to a more efficient, to have a chance to come back into the games and to try to make our defense more offensive.
Thank you for the time, Coach.
So, look at the spike velocity.
The numbers for Uando Leal, who's been a silver medal winner in the world championship back in the day with his native Cuba, a naturalised Brazilian, of course.
Ishikawa off the bench has come in and contributed seven attack points, but it's the Japan attack that has really been blunted through these first two sets and rare for Philippe Blaine,
to not have an awful lot to say there, but what can you say after Brazil's performance?
A little bit more to say than maybe he wanted, but he wanted to get back to his team and prepare them to start set number three.
He's got to find that magic.
Whatever they had in the beginning of set number one, to get out to that early 3-0 lead, those two three-point leads that they had in set number one, it's kind of escaped them, but Brazil really found themselves in every aspect of the game.
and has been playing very strong ever since.
They have been whispers around the world of volleyball.
I mean, it's not just you and me, Matt.
There's a little whiff of Brazil, perhaps not being where they once were after that quarterfinal exit in the volleyball nation's league and the Japan on the upswing, but this doesn't look like a meeting of one team on the way up and one team on the way down to me.
No, it certainly doesn't.
I mean, Brazil has responded.
And especially after being down two games to Nunn, to Cuba, and coming back to win the next three.
To a good position here.
Yeah, that really has given them a jolt.
Four sets they've won in a row, and they'll be well on course for five here, you would think.
Fernando gets them back in system.
Again, defensively really good from Rantaka, Hashid Nishida.
No, that's going to go out.
Well, if they can get their outside hitters firing, they've got a chance.
They need Nishida, we've been saying it all match long.
He had a great start, was very quiet in set number two.
But that could be a good sign, especially the sign that Japan needs here in set three.
Haven't seen much of a big old Felipe Roque so far.
Number 21 for Brazil.
Oh, nice fake, but they don't buy the fake.
That's good defending from Japan, and they're going to need to do some more though, and they can't get it.
Can't get it.
Lucas just so long.
Look where Fernando set that ball from.
All in the way, nearly at the sideline.
What is it about?
What is it about Lucas?
Everyone keeps saying, well, he's going to start to, his skills will start to erode at some point.
He's 36.
There's no sign of it at all.
Yeah, Nishida gets the better there of Leal, who didn't really have much of an opportunity to do much about that.
Leal so far inside to start that block move, and then he goes wide like that.
Takes one right off the forehead.
Nishida drills it, it's another nice ace.
Perfect.
And Nishida off to a very hot start here in set number three.
Two kills and a service ace.
Yesotales just look at that and say, ah, no, he's got another one.
And they do come in bunches with Eugene Nishida.
He won't hold back on this one.
Drilled it.
Really nice pick up that.
The crosscourt from Wallace doesn't work.
And Chicago goes for a bit of finesse, a bit of football from Fernando, but no.
They're not going to let him have that.
Got to appreciate the effort there from Fernando.
Got the ball up on that first contact, but watch it go straight into Wallace's chest that has to go over.
Fernando's got to work on his football skills a little bit.
Listen, if you're Brazilian, you know how to use your feet.
That's a given.
They made a fast start in set one.
Got picked back.
What Brazil need is a side out.
Get this guy out of the service rotation.
Get him out of there.
Tales picks that up.
It's a really nice pass.
Fernando goes back side with the set and Wallace finishes the job.
Really, really good pass from Tales.
Oh, it was an amazing pass.
And then this swing from Wallace just placing it precisely right down the line for that point in a much needed side out for Brazil.
Lucas as that sent back and then it's taken off the block and away in Japan, resolutely trying to dig in here.
All smiles from Sekita as Onodara takes care of business here.
Ishikawa.
Wallace de Souza.
Nice, the angle served there.
Ryan Takahashi runs into the block.
He'll have another go here.
The containing block is there.
He gets the better of it, but Wallace is there to keep it alive.
Luka Relly sets it up and lay it off.
Takes it off and Ishida's attempted dig.
Ishida in retrospect, maybe should have left that alone, but...
It's his touch, sends it out, and they back come Brazil.
Wallace doing a great job to keep this ball alive in the set from Luccarelli to his teammate.
They all get that point.
Pretty sure that was dropping in there anyway.
He had to try and make a play at it.
Wallace.
down the line to Takahashi Nishida is wiped out.
Absolutely wiped out.
Was that Flavio?
Was it Luccarelli?
Brazil don't care.
They'll take another stuff block.
Leal with the right hand.
Keeping it over just long enough to get that block point.
It's going to take blocks now for Brazil.
I think he's put too much on that.
Yeah, around Takahashi.
Sends that too deep.
Well, they've made the strong start, but they've been overhauled by Brazil already here in Japan.
We have to find solution of it, huh?
Okay?
Sometime or so, using push or, huh?
You can use many things, working with, huh?
There you go.
But we don't forget fight, also.
We don't play so much, so we can go, we can go, but we don't fight.
Off the timeout.
Here comes Wallace, Brazil 6-5.
Serving Yamamoto.
Sent back side, Nishida takes it off the block.
Side out.
Lael knows he's very close to getting a block on Nishida.
But you can see him reach back in and Nishida just targets the forearm and goes out of bounds.
As you say, he knows.
That's a couple of inches.
And he's got himself another block point.
Fine margins, always is in this game.
That's a pretty soft serve coming in from Onadira, who's got underneath that somehow, that is some rescue.
And then nothing doing there for Takahashi, who's denied at the baseline, and then a block.
Oh, it's gone out, it's spun away from Yamachi, thought he'd got himself a block point there, and it just took that wicked spin off court.
Leal scoring his 13th point of the match and he is not showing any signs of slowing down.
Taking swing after swing, scoring points for his side.
Leal, some of a zinger, nicely collected, Brian Takahashi.
No winner for him, but always kind of swing at that.
Would you believe it?
You know, Andy Leal from a mile back.
And now Brazil will look to transition.
Set it up on the inside.
Brilliant from Ishikawa back.
He can't keep it in play.
And they're just being...
Overworked here, Japan.
I mean, so strong defensively, but Brazil just keeps sending the heavy hitters out there, Adam.
Well, Leal wanted that one and Fernando knows who the hot hitter is.
He's setting Leal.
No matter where he is on the court, he's taking a swing at it.
That's a tough one for Sekita to deal with, yeah.
We'll do this one again.
That's good to see the referee taking responsibility of that.
I'm sorry guys, can we do this one again please?
bit quick on the whistle, wanted to call the double, but realized that Lukarelli was playing it back to his own side.
Players don't mind that.
Everybody makes a mistake.
He put his hands up, said, yeah, that's on me, and everyone's just going to get on with it.
Leal at 86 into the net.
Just trying to stick around here, Japan, and service errors will help.
Tales with a perfect service reception.
No winner there though for Flavio.
This time they've contained that in comes Ishikawa.
Does he catch the line?
And the answer to that is no, he does not.
Well, Ishikawa missed that opportunity.
Flavio reaches to the right side and Ishikawa misses to the wrist away.
You're playing Brazil.
Those are the kind of shots you've got to have.
Flavio serving Yamamoto, an easy take for him and an easy put away for Yamachi, uncontested.
Japan not utilizing their middles a lot in this match so it's good to see them get a point here and there.
Again, really nice pick up there from Lukarelli, who will get third touch on this.
Ooh, did that take anything on the way through?
They're saying no, and immediately Lukas is saying, you challenged that.
Lukas had big eyes on that.
Yeah, as soon as the challenge came in, Japan admitted to the touch.
We'll see the replay here, but right there off the pinky.
Yeah, Yamachi saying, yeah, that's on me.
Fernando.
10-8 Brazil.
He's mixing his serves up.
Sakita sends it over to Ishikawa.
That's picked up by Fernando down the line.
This will be Luccarelli looking at this one.
And I think he's overheated that one.
That goes wide.
Luccarelli just missing the sideline there as well.
There's just enough misses and service errors from Brazil to keep Japan within touching distance here.
But then Yamachi has got to make sure his serves go in, especially when it's as soft as that.
And he doesn't need anyone to tell him that.
Lukarelli then, 11-9.
Got to be side out Japan.
Just got to dig in here.
Stay close, Sekita under.
Intense pressure feeds Nishida and that won't drop their weight.
Well, it was all service reception.
The pass was not perfect.
Sekita did well just to give Nishida any kind of play at all, but the defenders were just lining up.
Yeah, Leal finally getting that one off of Nishida that he missed earlier.
And Sekita a little frustrated with this setting location there after that play was over.
Luccarelli at 12-9 Brazil.
Takahashi picking that one up.
Now, has Nishida got that?
No, he hasn't.
He hasn't.
I think this match has just gone away from Japan, just in these last two points.
Just a little off the net.
Nishida trying to make something of it, but just misses the inline.
Nishida out.
Kento Miara in for Japan.
Lukarelli serving at 13-9, desperately needed side out here for Japan.
Two of them going for that one.
Yamamoto setting from way, way, way back and Fernando sets up the pipe attack and that is just drilled by Lukarelli.
And again, Japan in disarray on their service reception and they've paid for it.
Lukarelli just hammers that ball into that open seam.
Lukareli serving Yamamoto.
Sekita has to move around a little bit.
Miara has to take a very, very clever swing at that because the blockers were lining up to send that back and he's been very creative with his swing.
Yeah, nice off-speed shot there from the opposite that just came in.
Brunos living every point there, isn't he, on the bench?
So Miara opening his account off the bench.
That's all he's going to have for his tally after he comes up with a service error.
Brazil with such a comfortable lead here.
Clever.
Nishikawa.
Yeah, very clever indeed, Nick.
Nishikawa changing up the pace.
Placing it precisely past the block of Wallace.
Well, how they would like a couple of aces here from Yuki Ishikawa.
For now, there's got some work to do there.
not the greatest of service receptions, and can they get themselves out of it?
They can because he lay out, you know, and lay out with great touch and depth on that swing.
Just lay out having a match.
That's his 16th point.
And finally showing that he can change the pace up a little bit and still be effective.
Wallace.
Talis has got that off the floor somehow.
Goodness only knows how.
Oh, that is a perfect push.
Luke Corelli.
Goodness me.
It's your fans' blockers deciding not to let's lay all their hands out.
Luke Corelli, excuse me.
Everything going the way of Brazil now?
That's OK.
You can see from the body language, he knows this.
There's no way back from this.
Six point deficit here in set number three.
Brazil really playing some strong volleyball.
Until Yoandil Leal, who had that last point, not look great as I incorrectly picked up.
You said it earlier, he's just having one of those games.
I mean, he's seeing everything big and slow and everything he's attempting.
It just happens like that somehow for you as a player.
Everything drops into place and it really has been working for Yoandil Leal today and the last 10 points.
I mean, it's been a wipeout.
Yeah, Brazil, behind the efforts of Leal, really up their level, just firing on all cylinders.
Everybody has contributed.
with stood the pressure from the inline for Japan and come right back with their own.
By Patak.
Drilled that, Thales.
By Ishikawa, who will actually come through the net, just to make sure that the Brazil libero is okay.
He is.
What are the dangers of
Standing that close.
Tal is getting that one right off of the chin.
He's going to take a second just to gather himself.
But smiles all around.
Yeah, he's OK. Part of the game.
Too big a hit from Wallace.
It's the consistency of the hitting from Wallace and from Luca Raleigh, and of course we talked about Yoendi Layal.
I mean, not been too many unforced errors from that gang of three this afternoon.
Ayres have been very limited.
Layal, Wallace, Luca Raleigh.
Takahashi tries to be clever.
It's the right idea.
Oh, Luccarelli improvising something there and then it's all gone wrong for Ishikawa.
Luccarelli trying to run a quick attack there.
He's seen Lucas do it for so long you wanted to get in on that action when Flavio wasn't there with the misconnection.
You know, it's good to see Japan smiling and seeing the funny side.
This actually sets up a huge third match for them in the pool phase against Cuba.
I mean, they've got to get something out of that, or they could face elimination.
Yeah, a nice little push there from Ran Takahashi.
That's crashing it down there wasn't it Flavio?
You know maybe falling two sets behind a Cuban is exactly what this Brazil squad needed.
You know they came in after and by their stands that indifferent volleyball nation's league they fall two down and everyone starts looking at them and I think they looked at themselves and said no no no we're better than this.
But since then they've just been inspired.
Character moment for sure and perhaps it's carried over into this match.
I mean this is going to be a statement victory for them that
Everybody else in the world championships is going to take note of.
Darlan.
We know what he can do from the service line.
It's another beauty.
Ran Takahashi picks it up, but when you're setting from there, you're asking for trouble, and sure enough, there is very little chance for Takahashi there as Miara was setting all the way back to our commentary position there.
It's impossible.
Very compromised situation for Japan.
Setting the ball from that far off the court.
This is some weapon to bring off the bench.
This really is.
I'll tell you, Darlan.
Darlan's bringing it when he serves.
There goes another one in it.
This is devastating.
Absolutely devastating.
Wow, what a serve.
Oh, that had everything.
Fly, spin, power, direction.
Tomio Miro Yamamoto could not deal with it at all, and there wouldn't have been many players in the world who could.
Darlan looking for another big one.
That's way too big.
But hey, that's job done.
That's another really good cameo.
Yeah, he gets the other boys on the bench.
And Brazil, three points from wrapping this thing up.
Takahashi.
Picked up by Leal.
Lukarelli.
No, that's nice.
From Ran Takahashi, Ishikawa.
No, that's picked up by Yoandil Leal.
And then they block him, but the block goes out.
So Wallace will claim himself another winner.
Miara was certainly there, one of a gang of three from Japan, and they could not keep it in play.
And Brazil,
Moved to within two points.
Fernando serving at 23-14.
What a professional job.
Renan Balzotto's squad have performed this afternoon.
It was a match you thought potentially could have been fraught with danger for Brazil.
and they've turned it into a comfortable straight sets victory.
You can't even say Japan have played particularly badly, but Brazil have really brought it today.
And so Yamachi with a little flash of defiance.
Well, that's all it is.
Gavacci with serve.
Thales picks that up.
And that's another one for Wallace.
And that brings up an awful lot of match points.
The longer it's gone on, there is a chasm has opened up between these two teams.
The Japan are staring down the barrel of a pretty comprehensive straight sets defeat here.
Lukarelli.
Sekita manages to set up Miara, and he's found himself a winner there.
Oh, Kento Miara.
Forcing Lukarelli to make a decision here.
Does he leave it?
Does he go for it?
And he decided to go for it.
That delays the moment.
Miara will be lining up to serve once we've got the moisture cleaned off the floor.
Yara serves Thales, that could be an overpass.
Fernando has somehow rescued it one-handed and Lucas puts it away and that point right there sums up Brazil's quality.